Guide to the Northwest Public Radio (NWPR) Audio Recordings 1973-1999
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Northwest Public Radio (NWPR) Audio Recordings
1973-1999
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Archives 287
Northwest Public Radio
9 Linear feet of shelf space 9 boxes
When the National Public Radio network began in 1971, KWSU was one of the initial members. Through the 1980s, translator stations were established throughout parts of the Washington, and in adjacent Idaho and Oregon, and a network of stations based out of WSU and soon including Tri-Cities (KFAE), University of Idaho (KUID) and others began to form. This network of stations took the name Northwest Public Radio. The audio recordings from Northwest Public Radio include not only finished radio programs, but also interviews taken for radio productions, short broadcast news items, and 'work' pieces that represent shows or presentations still in progress. A significant number of items are also recordings of WSU events.
Radio services at Washington State University date to 1922, when station KFAE began in December, 1922; that subsequently became KWSC and then KWSU in 1969 (after Washington State College had become Washington State University ten years earlier in 1959). In about 1950, it instituted a "tape network," locally produced programs which were distributed on recording tape to commercial and non-commercial broadcasters in the state. When the National Public Radio network began in 1971, KWSU was one of the initial members. Through the 1980s, translator stations were established throughout parts of the Washington, and in adjacent Idaho and Oregon, and a network of stations based out of WSU and soon including Tri-Cities (KFAE), University of Idaho (KUID) and others began to form. This network of stations took the name Northwest Public Radio. Programming for these radio stations has long been a mix of local programming and programming acquired from the various public broadcasting networks and program distribution services.
For a fuller history of Washington State University radio, please see Burt Harrison's 1993 "Washington State On The Air".
The audio recordings from Northwest Public Radio include not only finished radio programs, but also interviews taken for radio productions, short broadcast news items, and 'work' pieces that represent shows or presentations still in progress. A significant number of items are also recordings of WSU events, notably Murrow Symposia, Borah Symposia, convocations, and commencements.
The collection is organized into six series based on material types. Series 1 consists of 7" reel-to-reel tapes, series 3 is 10" tapes, and series 4 is 5" tapes. Series 2 is a small set of mini-disks, and Series 5 and Series 6 respectively are comprised of cassette tapes and digital audio tapes. Within each series, items are generally organized chronologically, with undated items at the end of each series, alphabetically by subject or responsible party. The exceptions to this is Series 1, which has two subseries of distinct programs, Northwest Perspectives (Subseries 1) and Talking Politics (Subseries 2) and then has a Subseries 3 organized as above. Similarly, Series 6 has an unofficial subseries consisting of Classic Northwest programs, given its own numbering.
This collection is open and available for research use.
The audio recordings of Northwest Public Radio (NWPR) were given by that department to the University Archives on February 19th, 2010 as UA2010-01.
During processing, a small number of nationally produced recordings were discarded, as were a number of musical program digital audio tapes (DATs).
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Northwest Public Radio; Washington State University.
Public radio -- Washington (State)
Washington (State); Media and Communication; Colleges and Universities
- Series 1: 7 inch inch reel to reel audio tapes
  - Subseries 1.1: Northwest Perspectives
    - Baltezore, Jay, 1988 September 30 (Box 1, Item 1)
    - Harrison, Dale, 1988 October 10 (Box 1, Item 2)
    - Unidentified, 1988 October 17 (Box 1, Item 3)
    - Unidentified, 1988 October 24 (Box 1, Item 4)
    - Unidentified, 1988 October 31 (Box 1, Item 5)
    - Harrison, Dale, 1988 October 31 (Box 1, Item 6)
    - Unidentified, 1988 November 07 (Box 1, Item 7)
    - Baltezore, Jay, 1988 November 14 (Box 1, Item 8)
    - Unidentified, 1988 November 28 (Box 1, Item 9)
    - Morgan, Pat, 1988 December 12 (Box 1, Item 10)
    - MK, 1988 December 26 (Box 1, Item 11)
    - Compton, Charles, 1989 January 02 (Box 1, Item 12)
    - Baltezore, Jay, 1989 January 09 (Box 1, Item 13)
    - Unidentified, 1989 January 16 (Box 1, Item 14)
    - Unidentified, 1989 January 23 (Box 1, Item 15)
    - Compton, Charles, 1989 January 30 (Box 1, Item 16)
    - Unidentified, 1989 February 06 (Box 1, Item 17)
    - Kasavant, Ken, 1989 February 13 (Box 1, Item 18)
    - Compton, Charles, 1989 February 20 (Box 1, Item 19)
    - Unidentified, 1989 February 27 (Box 1, Item 20)
    - Unidentified, 1989 March 06 (Box 1, Item 21)
    - Unidentified, 1989 March 20 (Box 1, Item 22)
    - Harrison, Dale, 1989 April 03 (Box 1, Item 23)
    - Harrison, Dale, 1989 April 03 (Box 1, Item 24)
    - Compton, Charles, 1989 April 10 (Box 1, Item 25)
    - Dumin, Fred, 1989 April 17 (Box 1, Item 26)
    - Unidentified, 1989 April 24 (Box 1, Item 27)
    - Orlich, Donald, 1989 May 01 (Box 1, Item 28)
    - Unidentified, 1989 May 08 (Box 1, Item 29)
    - Unidentified, 1989 May 15 (Box 1, Item 30)
    - Unidentified, 1989 May 22 (Box 1, Item 31)
    - Unidentified, 1989 May 29 (Box 1, Item 32)
    - White, Tony, 1989 June 19 (Box 1, Item 33)
    - Krantz, Grover, 1989 June 26 (Box 1, Item 34)
    - Miller, 1989 September 03 (Box 1, Item 35)
    - Unidentified, 1989 September 17 (Box 1, Item 36)
    - Unidentified, 1989 September 24 (Box 2, Item 37)
    - Unidentified, 1989 October 15 (Box 2, Item 38)
    - Harrison, Dale, 1989 October 22 (Box 2, Item 39)
    - King, Doug, 1989 October 22 (Box 2, Item 40)
    - Unidentified, 1989 November 12 (Box 2, Item 41)
    - Harrison, Dale, 1989 November 19 (Box 2, Item 42)
    - Unidentified, 1989 November 19 (Box 2, Item 43)
    - Unidentified, 1990 January 07 (Box 2, Item 44)
    - Unidentified, 1990 January 14 (Box 2, Item 45)
    - Harrison, Dale, 1990 January 21 (Box 2, Item 46)
    - Gorton, Slade, 1990 January 28 (Box 2, Item 47)
    - Joyce, Ed, 1990 February 04 (Box 2, Item 48)
    - Massey, Doug, 1990 February 11 (Box 2, Item 49)
    - Smith, Charles, 1990 February 18 (Box 2, Item 50)
    - Compton, Charles, 1990 February 22 (Box 2, Item 51)
    - Unidentified, 1990 March 04 (Box 2, Item 52)
    - Unidentified, 1990 March 11 (Box 2, Item 53)
    - Joyce, Ed, 1990 March 18 (Box 2, Item 54)
    - Massey, Doug, 1990 March 25 (Box 2, Item 55)
    - Unidentified, 1990 April 01 (Box 2, Item 56)
    - Compton, Charles, 1990 April 08 (Box 2, Item 57)
    - Unidentified, 1990 April 15 (Box 2, Item 58)
    - Joyce, Ed, 1990 April 22 (Box 2, Item 59)
    - Limrick, Pat, 1990 April 29 (Box 2, Item 60)
    - Unidentified, 1990 June 03 (Box 2, Item 61)
    - Compton, Charles, 1990 June 10 (Box 2, Item 62)
    - Unidentified, 1990 June 17 (Box 2, Item 63)
    - Joyce, Ed, 1990 June 24 (Box 2, Item 64)
    - Compton, Charles, 1990 July 09 (Box 2, Item 65)
    - Kirshenman, Fred, undated (Box 2, Item 66)
    - McKay, Gordon, undated (Box 2, Item 67)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 2, Item 68)
  - Subseries 1.2: Talking Politics
    - Pall, Linda, 1979's (Box 2, Item 69-72)
    - Pall, Linda, 1980's (Box 3, Item 73-77)
    - Pall, Linda, 1981's (Box 3, Item 78-81)
    - Pall, Linda, 1982's (Box 3, Item 82)
    - Pall, Linda, undated (Box 3, Item 83-86)
  - Subseries 1.3: Miscellaneous
    - Kirkley, Donald - Conv. with H.L Mencken, 1948 June 30 (Box 3, Item 87)
    - Vogel Symposium - Mr. Schoeffels, wheat farmer, Wilbur, WA, 1973 March 26 (Box 3, Item 88)
    - Murrow Symposium - Sevareid/Ashmore, 1973 April 27 (Box 3, Item 89-90)
    - Jackson, Keith - Commencement Address, 1978 June 03 (Box 3, Item 91)
    - Herbeck - The Palouse Indians, 1980 January (Box 3, Item 92)
    - Morgan, Patrick - Soviet Review, 1980 (Box 3, Item 93-94)
    - Frey - Criminal Justice, 1980 (Box 3, Item 95-96)
    - Buckingham, Peter - Historical Perspectives, 1980 (Box 3, Item 97-99)
    - Black issues and concerns, 1981 April 02 (Box 3, Item 100)
    - Redford, Robert - Convocation, 1981 October 16 (Box 3, Item 101)
    - Smith, Ray - Pullman Schools, 1981 (Box 3, Item 102)
    - Kicza, Jogn - Latin America, 1981 (Box 3, Item 103)
    - True, Terry - On Drugs, 1981 (Box 3, Item 104)
    - Harrison, Dale - News stories, 1988 May 01 (Box 3, Item 105)
    - Harrison, Dale - News stories, 1988 May 05 (Box 3, Item 106)
    - Messerschmidt, David - Technology and the Schools, 1988 May 05 (Box 3, Item 107)
    - Kelser, Cherylyn - Harpsicord, 1988 December 23 (Box 3, Item 108)
    - Joyce, Ed - Idaho house/senate Leg. Dist. #5: elections, 1990 October 05 (Box 4, Item 109)
    - Kreidler, Margaret - W.C. Commission Candidates Forum, 1990 November 05 (Box 4, Item 110)
    - NPAN Regional - 6 features, 1990 November 28 (Box 4, Item 111)
    - BDH - News stories, 1990 (Box 4, Item 112-113)
    - Nez Perce Artists - SAPATQ'AYN, 1991 (Box 4, Item 114-116)
    - Gardner, Booth - Commencement Address, 1991 May 11 (Box 4, Item 117)
    - Historian, Hanford - Hanford History, 1991 September 20 (Box 4, Item 118)
    - Serafin, Barry - Interview after WSU Pres. Convocation, 1991 October 07 (Box 4, Item 119)
    - Banse - Election Coverage, 1991 November 06 (Box 4, Item 120)
    - Primary Election, 1992 (Box 4, Item 121)
    - Nell Lake / NPAN - Spotted Owl in Congress, 1992 May 21 (Box 4, Item 122)
    - Lohet, Ingrid - Chesan Mine, 1992 June 12 (Box 4, Item 123)
    - Compton, Charlie - Sid Morrison post-election interview, 1992 September 23 (Box 4, Item 124)
    - Messerschmidt, David - NPAN Election Night Info., 1992 November 03 (Box 4, Item 125)
    - Kreidler, Margaret - Tom Foley/ Marlyn Derby Election Special, 1992 November 05 (Box 4, Item 126)
    - Honig, Doug - Horizons- legal issues, 1992 (Box 4, Item 127)
    - Blazek, Mary Lou - Hanford Technical Steering Panel, undated (Box 4, Item 128)
    - Harrison, Dale - Work Tape Compilation, undated (Box 4, Item 129)
    - IAL - Collective Bargaining, 19uu April 15 (Box 4, Item 130)
    - Kjellander, Paul - Silver City / Rosalie Sorrel / Unidentified, undated (Box 4, Item 131)
    - Lowry, Mike, Governor - State of State, undated (Box 4, Item 132)
    - Messerschmidt, David - Port Angeles: Ringside on the Pacific Rim, undated (Box 4, Item 133)
    - Murrow, Edward - American Legion vs. ACLU, undated (Box 4, Item 134)
    - Murrow, Edward - This I Believe, undated (Box 4, Item 135)
    - Vidal, Gore - Face to Face, undated (Box 4, Item 136)
    - WSU - Artist Ross Coates, undated (Box 4, Item 137)
    - Education Reform, undated (Box 4, Item 138)
    - Northwest Area Features, 19uu May 16 (Box 4, Item 139)
    - Prop. 1, undated (Box 4, Item 140)
    - Storytelling, undated (Box 4, Item 141)
- Series 2: Mini-disks
  - Feature Disk 1 - bones, kid study interview, pay equity, etc., 1996 (Box 4, Item 1)
  - OAFP, Fall 1998 (Box 4, Item 2)
  - Features - Kid food, undated (Box 4, Item 3)
  - Nez Perce Grant, undated (Box 4, Item 4)
- Series 3: 10 inch reel to reel audio tapes
  - Dale Harrison, John Donnely - The Challenge of Global Poverty, 1981 March 04 (Box 5, Item 1)
  - Dale Harrison, Larry Branen - Infant and materna1 nutrition, 1981 March 12 (Box 5, Item 2)
  - Morning Edition - Mt. St. Helens, 1 year later, 1981 May 18 (Box 5, Item 3-5)
  - Spellman, Governor - State of the State, 1983 January 10 (Box 5, Item 6)
  - Murrow Symposium KWSU - Opening Remarks (reel 1), 1983 April 22 (Box 5, Item 7)
  - Murrow Symposium KWSU - The Impact of the Murrow Heritage (reel 2), 1983 April 22 (Box 5, Item 8)
  - Murrow Symposium KWSU - From the London Blitz to Beirut Battles (reel 3), 1983 April 23 (Box 5, Item 9)
  - Murrow Symposium KWSU - The News and the Messenger (reel 4), 1983 April 23 (Box 5, Item 10)
  - Murrow Symposium KWSU - Keynote Address - Diane Sawyer (reel 5), 1983 April 22 (Box 5, Item 11)
  - Murrow Symposium KWSU - Mass Media and Government: How Adversarial?, 1983 April 23 (Box 5, Item 12)
  - Murrow Symposium KWSU - Murrow Symposium - Reel 6 continued, 1983 April 23 (Box 6, Item 13)
  - Joyce, Ed - James Farmer Speech, 1985 February 21 (Box 6, Item 14)
  - Smith Inaugural - Inaugural Speech, 1985 March 21 (Box 6, Item 15)
  - Weekend Edition - Unidentified, 1985 October 19 (Box 6, Item 16-17)
  - SME Final Show - John, Perry, Vince, 1985 November 23 (Box 6, Item 18)
  - SME Final Show - Final Show, 1985 November 30 (Box 6, Item 19)
  - Bob and Bill, 1988 May 02 (Box 6, Item 20)
  - Northwest perspectives - Reporters and the reactor, 1989 June 05 (Box 6, Item 21)
  - Compton, Charles - Baugher-Newhouse Promo, Senate Race, 1990 October 31 (Box 6, Item 22)
  - All Stations - Election Special, 1990 November 01 (Box 6, Item 23)
  - Joyce, Ed - Borah Symposium, 1991 February 20 (Box 6, Item 24)
  - Joyce, Ed - Borah Symposium and News, 1991 March 08 (Box 7, Item 25)
  - Murrow Symposium - Murrow Symposium, 1991 April 01 (Box 7, Item 26)
  - Critical Condition Series - Best Of Seattle After Noon, 1991 September 13 (Box 7, Item 27)
  - Folkmasters #11, 1991 December 15 (Box 7, Item 28)
  - Borah Symposium - Borah Symposium, 1992 February 10 (Box 7, Item 29)
  - Nader, Ralph, 1992 February 20 (Box 7, Item 30)
  - Borah Symposium - Borah Symposium, 1992 March 11 (Box 7, Item 31)
  - Daggett, Dr. Bill - Educational Reform, 1992 March 24 (Box 7, Item 32)
  - Borah Symposium - Borah Symposium, 1992 April 06 (Box 7, Item 33)
  - Sikes, Alfred (FCC Chairman) - Alfred Sikes Speech, Murrow Symposium, 1992 April 24 (Box 7, Item 34)
  - Campaign Forum - Senate Forum part 1, 1992 August 01 (Box 7, Item 35)
  - Campaign Forum - Senate Forum part 2, 1992 August 01 (Box 7, Item 36)
  - Campaign Forum - Candidates Forum part 1, 1992 August 01 (Box 8, Item 37)
  - Candidates Forum part 2 and/or classical music, 1992 August 01 (Box 8, Item 38)
  - Blethen, Frank - Gubernatorial debate, 1992 October 16 (Box 8, Item 39)
  - Stimpson, Catherine - Post-Modernsim, 1993 January 01 (Box 8, Item 40)
  - Ashby, Leroy, 1993 February 17 (Box 8, Item 41)
  - AIDs Benefit - AIDs Benefit, undated (Box 8, Item 42)
  - Compton, Charles - Snake River, Drawdown Forum, 19uu March 16 (Box 8, Item 43)
  - Harrison, Dale - Work Tape, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Item 44)
  - Honig, Doug and Messerschmidt, David - The Once and Future Northwest, 19uu September 02 (Box 8, Item 45)
  - Kreidler, M. - 9th district candidates forum, undated (Box 8, Item 46)
  - La Duke, Winona - Winona La Duke Speech, Quincentenniel, undated (Box 8, Item 47)
  - Morning Edition - AMPEX-- daily recordings, undated (Box 8, Item 48)
  - Morning Edition - AMPEX-- daily recordings, undated (Box 9, Item 49)
  - Nichols, Scott - "gay guy", 19uu November 12 (Box 9, Item 50)
  - Northwest Portrait - Northwest Portrait, undated (Box 9, Item 51)
  - Schorr, Daniel - Daniel Schorr and/or classical music, undated (Box 9, Item 52)
  - Trotter, Kathleen - SPI Forum, 19uu December 14 (Box 9, Item 53)
  - Watson, Paul, undated; after 1991 (Box 9, Item 54)
- Series 4: 5 inch inch reel to reel audio tapes
  - Science in the News / Morning Edition - Chinese bigfoots / news clips, 1985 (Box 9, Item 1)
  - News: anti-Sandinistas, Nicaragua, El Salvador, 1986 (Box 9, Item 2)
  - Agricultural news, 1986 (Box 9, Item 3)
  - Gunther Schuller interview, 1986 January 30 (Box 9, Item 4)
  - Goodspeed, Nancy - News: UI boiler, Wheat shipping, others, 1980s (Box 9, Item 5)
  - Blakesly, Bethel - Summer News, undated (Box 9, Item 6)
  - Callahan, Scott - News, summer/fall, undated (Box 9, Item 7)
  - Harrison, Burt - Literary Scrapbook: H.L. Mencken, undated (Box 9, Item 8)
  - Hodge - Teaching Shakespeare in Idaho High Schools, undated (Box 9, Item 9)
  - Ludlum, Annie - Paul Heyne Interview, Economic best seller, undated (Box 9, Item 10)
  - WSU artist Ross Coates, undated (Box 9, Item 11)
  - Interview: David Grimes, WSU Fire Captain, undated (Box 9, Item 12)
  - Jim - Interview: Ron Johnson, USDA-APHIS, undated (Box 9, Item 13)
- Series 5: Audio cassette tapes
  - 6 boxed tapes - Murrow Symposium: Women in communication, Nimmo lunch, Leonard dinner, Garcia Keynote, 1980 (Box 9, Item 1980)
  - 10 bundled tapes - Murrow Symposium, 1981 (Box 9, Item 1981)
- Series 6: DAT (digital audio recording) tapes
  - NWPPC Meeting, 1992 December 09 (Item 1)
  - News/produced pieces - infant immunization, child violence, etc., 1995-1996 (Item 2)
  - Washington Idaho Symphony, 1995-1996 (Item 3-4)
  - Pickett, John - Faculty Recital Series, 1996 February 14 (Item 5)
  - Roger Briggs interview, 1996 February 26 (Item 6)
  - New Vistas - Hilary Field Interview, 1996 (Item 7)
  - Consort Columbia, 1997 (Item 8)
  - Sehnelle, Robert - News - Apple orchards, poison, ontrovert, etc, 1997-1998 (Item 9)
  - OAFP - Hearts of Space, 1998 February 14 (Item 10)
  - WWDTM - WWDTM, 1999 September 16 (Item 11)
  - Alcohol Series, 1999 (Item 12)
  - Teresa (last name unclear) - Hate Groups, undated (Item 13)
  - Sports Camp Audio, undated (Item 14)
  - Wharton, Bill and Linda, undated (Item 15)
  - Wilson and Cazavarro, undated (Item 16-18)
  - Windows on Our community - Farmers market, undated (Item 19)
  - Windows on Our community - Work, undated (Item 20)
  - Classic Northwest Program - Numbered 1-13, #5 missing at time of donation to Archives, undated (Item CN1-CN13)